准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
饼干义卖
大比拼
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
科学童子军  听好了
All right, Science Scouts, listen up
这次的义卖严肃得不得了
This here business is serious as a rattlesnake bite
所以可不能搞砸了
so let's make sure we don't mess it up
要是赚得够多
If we earn enough money
最后就能有钱去火星旅行了
we can finally afford that trip to Mars
快出发卖饼干吧
Now, get out there and sell these biscuits
遵命  科学队长珊迪
Aye, aye, Science Master Sandy
吵什么吵啊
What's all that racket?
你们好  女士
Good day, ma'ams
想不想来买点科学童子军饼干啊
Would you like to buy some Science Scouts biscuits?
科学
Science?
那种玩意就是一派胡言
That malarkey ain't real
我那个年代有炼金术
Back in my day, we had alchemy
对我们来说早就够用了
and that was good enough for us
玛丽  今天都星期三了
Mary, it's Wednesday
来削掉我脚上的肿块
Time to shave down my bunions
谁啊
Who is it?
你好  先生
Good day, sir
你是屋主吗
Are you the man of the house?
不是
Oh, no
主人在休眠
The master is in repose
那你的主人应该会愿意醒过来
Well, perhaps your master would like to wake up
尝尝新鲜现烤的饼干吧
to some fresh-baked biscuits
不会的
Oh, no
他可不喜欢固体食物
He doesn't care for solid foods
不过主人会口渴
Master does get thirsty though
抱歉
Sorry
没事
No problem
拉里健身房
你好啊  小姐兄弟
Sup, little lady bro?
你好  先生
Yes, hello, sir
有没有考虑过买点科学童子军饼
Have you considered
purchasing some Science Scout bis--
我是说  能量棒
I mean, energy bars?
可以帮你强身健体
They will fill you with the fuel for fitness
拉里我确实得补补碳水
Well, Larry does need to carbo load
我买十二盒
I'll take a dozen boxes
好耶
Yeah
卖出第一份了
We got our first sale
我关节好疼啊
My aching knuckles
今天一定敲了一百万扇门吧
I must have knocked on a million doors today
钱
Money?
蟹蟹的美味小点心
Tasty morsels for the Krabsy
别乱碰
Claws off
这钱可是科学童子军的
That money belongs to the Science Scouts
还是我卖饼干赚来的
I got it from selling biscuits
卖饼干是吗
Selling biscuitses, eh?
昨天的饼干义卖赚得不错
All right, that was some
fancy biscuit hawking yesterday
但今天  我们要
but today, we're going to--
海绵宝宝呢
Where's SpongeBob?
他在那边陪着蟹老板
He's over there with Mr. Krabs
跟那条愁眉苦脸的章鱼
and that sad-looking octopus
海绵宝宝  你在干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
他是在为裤头村顶级饼干义卖队效命
He's working with the premier
biscuit-selling team in Bikini Bottom
就这么回事
that's what he's doing
不好意思啊
Now, if you don't mind
我们还得卖蟹堡涂鸦呢
we've got some Krusty Doodles to sell
蟹堡涂鸦
Krusty Doodles?
就是不新鲜的蟹黄堡面包而已
These are just stale Krabby Patty buns
完美陈酿  撒有肉桂
Aged to perfection and sprinkled with cinnamon
给我滚
Now, scram
这里可是蟹堡童子军的地盘
This is Krusty Scout territory
想得美  这里可是科学童子军的地盘
Oh, no, this is Science Scout territory
是吗
Oh, yeah?
要不来打个赌
How about a little wager?
谁今天饼干卖得最多  谁就能继续卖
Whoever sells the most biscuits today
gets to keep selling
输的那队以后永远不准再卖饼干
And the loser leaves the biscuit biz forever
一言为定
Deal
不会吧
Oh, no
有个来推销的
A solicitor
朋友  想不想来买
Friend, how would you like to buy
全海洋最有收藏价值的点心呢
the most collectible snack in the whole ocean?
都是全新未拆封的薄荷饼干哦
They're mint biscuits in mint condition
你说全新未拆封吗
Mint, you say?
想尝到饼干真正的滋味
If you want real biscuit flavor
不如来尝尝看蟹堡涂鸦
try a Krusty Doodle instead
你的角色扮演太烂了
Your cosplay is terrible
我不买
I'll pass
给我来三盒
Give me three boxes
慢着  章鱼哥先生
Avast, Mr. Squidward
想卖饼干得再可爱点才行
If you want to move biscuits, you gotta be cuter
来  我帮你
Here, I'll help you
好了
There you go
这下你可爱不少了  看吧
Now you're adorable, see?
我什么都看不到
I can't see anything
视网膜脱落了
My retinas detached
珍珍啊  你好可爱
Oh, Pearl, don't you look cute?
谢了  泡芙老师
Thanks, Mrs. Puff
我在卖饼干
I'm selling biscuits
给我的童子军队筹钱上火星
so my scout troop can go to Mars
真可爱
Adorable
我找找钱包
Let me get my purse
等一下
Wait a minute
不如来买我的饼干吧
Buy my biscuits instead
你眼睛怎么了  章鱼哥
What's wrong with your eyes, Squidward?
你又搞砸了
You're blowing it again
我来给你正确示范
I'll show you how it's done
你好啊  我可爱的阿芙
Hello, my sweet Puffikins
不来我这买点饼干吗
Won't you buy some biscuits
只有我这只螃蟹偷走了你的心哦
from the only crab to ever steal your heart?
感觉还不错
Well, that does sound nice
别听他的
Don't listen to him
我的饼干才更好  泡芙老师
My biscuits are better, Mrs. Puff
别听她的
Don't listen to her
自己找人家义卖去
Find your own house to sell at
来我这买饼干才对
Get your biscuit right here
买我的才对
Come on, buy mine
想不想来买点饼干
Would you like to buy some biscuits?
不想
No
你确定不想买饼干吗
Are you sure you don't want to buy some biscuits?
确定
Yes
我们的超辣肉桂饼干买不买
How about our super spicy cinnamon biscuits?
怎么大家都不叫了
Why did everyone stop yelling?
急诊
看来这次的饼干生意我赢定了
Well, looks like the biscuit business is all mine now
绝对不能让他赢了
We ain't letting him win this one
加把劲  科学童子军
Come on, Science Scouts
你还是罢休吧  珊迪
Why not let it go, Sandy?
反正镇上就只剩一个地方能卖饼干了
There's only one place left in town to sell to anyway
养老院
the old folks home
你得把饼干卖给所有老人家
and you'd have to sell to every single oldie there
才能打败我
to beat me
看来全靠你了  珍珍
Looks like it's up to you, Pearl
什么
What?
等等  什么
Wait, what?
那是我的计划
That was my plan
这东西应该是你的吧
I believe this belongs to you
我的饼干
My biscuits
荫凉滩
疗养院
搞破坏最爽了
Nothing beats sabotage-y
我的刹车
Me brakes?
全都被破坏了
They've been sabotagied
优惠炸药
床垫厂
谁想要饼干
Who wants biscuits?
你呢  先生
What about you, mister?
想不想来找我这可爱小女孩买饼干呢
Buy some biscuits from a sweet little girl?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
大伙的假牙都不见了
Everyone's chompers have gone missing
没牙还怎么咀嚼饼干
How are we supposed to chew biscuits
if we ain't got no teeth?
我好像把大家的假牙都借走了
Looks like I borrowed everyone's dentures
快来买软软糯糯的饼干糊
Get your biscuit mush right here, nice and soft
已经咀嚼过了  可以不用再嚼了
We do the chewing so you don't have to
好耶
Oh, yeah
手工饼干
Homemade biscuits
好美味的糊糊
Lovely mush
看来就这样了
Well, I guess that's it
只能收工了
Time to call it a day
活到老学到老  小珍珍
Live and learn, Pearly girl
你们卖饼干注定要玩完
That's just the way the biscuit bounces
给我的饼干再咀嚼糊一点
Make mine extra mushy
你好啊  小珍珍
Hey there, Pearly girl
很遗憾你这次比拼没赢
Sorry you didn't win the competition
我可还没输
I didn't lose yet
是吗
You didn't?
对  我想起来还能再找一个人卖饼干
Nope, I realized there was one more person to sell to
而且我正好知道怎么说服他买东西
and I know how to get him to buy anything
有种不祥的预感
I don't like where this is going
老爸
Daddy
买我的饼干
Buy my biscuits
老爸
Daddy
我不能
No, I can't--
我
I--
好好好  我这就买你的饼干
All right, I'll buy your biscuits
谢了  老爸
Thanks, Daddy
我们要去火星了
We're going to Mars
还挺好吃
These are tasty
穿越太空之后
先前的饼干义卖赚得真不少
That was some mighty fine selling
科学童子军
Science Scouts
终于有钱可以大胆扩张
Now, we can afford to boldly expand
挺进新的饼干市场了
into new biscuit markets
万岁
Hooray
你们好  地球生物
Greetings, Earth creatures
要买点太空饼干吗
Would you like to purchase some Astro Biscuits?
我们在攒钱去地球旅行
We are raising money for a trip to Earth
好吧
OK, y'all
要是赚得够多
If we earn enough money
最后就能有钱去木星了
we can afford a trip to Jupiter
驾校幸存学员
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我的船整整一里都卡在倒挡
My boat was stuck in reverse for a whole mile
我向左转  开上了一座超大弹簧山
I turned left
and backed into a mountain of giant springs
太强了  兄弟
Righteous, dude
然后船往前弹了过去
Then, the boat sprung forward
开上了还没完工的大桥
up onto an unfinished bridge
在那里弹弹跳跳
where we bounced--
穿梭在桥墩之间
from column to column
然后被一个起重机钩住了
and got caught on the hook of a construction crane
挂在上面荡过整座城市
where we swung out over the city
最后着陆到了个垃圾箱里
until we landed on a garbage dumpster
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
谢谢你夸张地复述上一节驾驶课
for that melodramatic retelling
of our last driving lesson
荣幸之至
My pleasure
墙突然就冒出来了
Wall came out of nowhere
同学们安静
Settle down, class
我很高兴能宣布今天
I'm elated to announce that today
又多了一个新同学
we have a new driving student with us
进来自我介绍一下吧
Come in and introduce yourself
非常感谢你能给我这个机会
Thank you so much for this opportunity
加速绿灯是我的名字
Acceleration T. Greenlight's the name
教会学员驾驶就是我的拿手好戏
and teaching driving is my game
什么
What?
我是绿灯驾校的所有者及经营者
I'm the owner and operator
of the Greenlight Driving School
先生  你可以
All right, mister, you can just--
我能保证大家都能领到驾照
And I guarantee a driver's license to anyone
绕着教学楼开一圈  包开包会
after only one drive around the block
而且学费只要泡芙老师的一半
and at half the price that Mrs. Puff charges
我先前对付过他这种家伙
I've dealt with his kind before
不行  不能再回去坐牢了
No, I am not going back to the slammer
绕教学楼开一圈  包你领驾照
Once around the block and your license is a lock
跟我来
Follow me
这边走
Right this way
同学们  你们要去哪
Class, where are you going?
别听他的
Don't listen to him
滑浪学校
回来
Come back
还要上课呢
We have a lesson
欢迎  白痴们
Welcome, suckers--
我是说  学员们
I mean, students--
绿灯驾校
前来就读绿灯驾校
to the Greenlight Driving School
所有人居然全都抛下我了
I can't believe everyone left me
并不是所有人
Not everyone
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
早该知道的
I might have known
墙
没问题
No problem
当心
Careful
小心
Watch out
交给我
I got this
慢点
Slow down
刹车  刹车
Brakes, brakes
抱歉
Sorry
海神王啊
Oh, Neptune
给你吧
Here you go
这是今天的学费
That's for today's lesson
可别一下子都花光了
Don't spend it all in one place
下周再见
See you next week
没错  绕着教学楼开一圈
Yes siree, once around the block
恭喜你了
Congratulations
裤头村驾照
史酷特
裤头村
酷乐湖1434号
你成功领到驾照了
You're a licensed driver
太棒了
Gnarly
我想要驾照
I want a license
我也要
Me too
那个加速绿灯
Acceleration T. Greenlight
账单
Bills?
逾期  欠债
Overdue, delinquent?
不还清就去死
"Pay or die?"
一周就教一次海绵宝宝还怎么还债啊
How will I ever pay these bills
teaching SpongeBob only once a week?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
快上船学下一课
Hop in for your next lesson
你搞错了吧  泡芙老师
You're mistaken, Mrs. Puff
我今天不上课的
Today's not my lesson day
我刚把你升级成超级黄金学员了
I just upgraded you to Super Gold status
以后你每天都得来上课
You'll have lessons every day
当然相应的费用该付还得付
with the corresponding fees, of course
好  可我
Yeah, but I--
我要去上班
I'm on my way to work
快上船
Get in the boat
是  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff
快开船
Now, drive
遵命
Aye, aye
我不敢看
I can't look
停
Stop
快看啊
Looky there
是那家开得特成功的驾校
It's that really successful driving school
谢了
Thanks
谢谢
太棒了
Great
我会开船了
I can drive now
谢了
Thanks
你好啊  输家
Hello, loser
放心  泡芙老师
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff
我对你忠诚  而且只对你忠诚
I'm loyal to you and only you
谢了  海绵
Thank you, Sponge
宝宝
Bob
今天上的驾驶课可真漫长啊  小蜗
That was a long day's driving lesson, Gary
海绵宝宝  来上下一节课了
SpongeBob, time for your next lesson
好是好  可现在都大半夜了
Yeah, but it's the middle of the night
今晚的课程是
Tonight's lesson is
半夜行船
Late-night driving
当然还得再额外上交课程费
Of course, there'll be an extra fee
快点
Hurry up
来了  泡芙老师
Coming, Mrs. Puff
半夜行船的重中之重就是保持清醒
The most important part
of night driving is staying awake
放点大声的音乐
Some loud music
再来点咖啡就行了
And coffee should do it
小心点
Watch it
别挡道
Get off the road
危险  雾堤
明天早上上课再见
I'll see you in the morning for tomorrow's lesson
可明天星期天啊
But tomorrow is Sunday
你星期天也得来上驾驶课  小傻瓜
It's your Sunday driver lesson, you silly billy boy
对  我是小傻瓜
Yeah, I'm a silly billy boy
溜冰场
今天总算能自己做主了
Finally, a day to myself
今天的课程是冰上行船
Today's lesson, ice driving
朝打滑方向打方向盘
Turn into the slide
松开油门
Foot off the gas
向海神王祈祷
Pray to Neptune
还真的有用
That actually worked
我正好就需要独处的时光
Just what I needed, some me time
又要上什么课了
What lesson now?
山路行船课
Mountain driving lesson
下面的小心
Look out below
医院
急诊
护士  我现在要拉开他的拉链
Nurse, I'm unzipping him now
等一下  医生
Hold on, Doctor
泡芙老师  你在里面吗
Mrs. Puff, are you in there?
你在里面吗
Are you in there?
别傻了  海绵宝宝
Don't be silly, SpongeBob
我怎么会塞得进去
How would I fit in there?
对啊  里面的空间只能装得下一位
Yeah, there's only room for one
我
me
派大星
Patrick
来上你下一节驾驶课了
Time for your next driving lesson
可是泡芙老师  我完全破产了
But, Mrs. Puff, I'm totally broke
再也没钱交学费了
I can't pay for any more lessons
看来我走投无路了
Well, I guess it's the end of the road for me
咱能吃点午饭吗
Can we get some lunch now?
你肚子空荡荡的
Your stomach is empty
停业
Out of business
我还以为我的驾校能开一辈子
I thought my school would last forever
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
光他自己一个海绵就是拆迁队了
the one-sponge wrecking crew
等一下  海绵宝宝
Hold on, SpongeBob
有了
That's it
原来我居然一直都做错了
I can't believe I've been going about this all wrong
裤头村驾照
小蜗
裤头村
贝壳街124号
上路愉快  蜗牛
Happy trails, snail
这不是泡芙老师吗
Well, if it isn't Mrs. Puff
什么风把你吹来我这所小驾校的
What brings you to my humble driving school?
你说你随随便便就能让学员领到驾照
You say you can get any student a license
只要上一节课就行了吗
with just one lesson?
肯定没错
Guaranteed
我这边要给你个冤大头
Well, I've got a live one for you
祝你好运
Good luck
你多半用得上
You'll need it
领到驾照的秘诀
The trick to being a licensed driver
就在于绕着教学楼开一圈
is going once around the block
你在干什么
What are you doing?
放我出来
Let me out
我还没学  放我出来呢
I haven't learned "let me out" yet
不过可以给你见识一下我学到的知识
but I'll show you what I have learned
停
Stop
停下这艘船  我求你了
Stop this boat, I beg of you
当好乘客的秘诀就是放弃一切控制权
The trick to being a passenger is to give up all control
警察局
我开得怎么样
How's my driving?
这不是海绵宝宝吗
Well, if it isn't SpongeBob
你逮到了恶名昭彰的加速绿灯
And you've captured
the notorious Acceleration T. Greenlight
通缉
他在海底四处倒卖假驾照
He's been selling phony driver's licenses
throughout the seabed
裤头村驾照
懒惰鬼玛丽
助步器老头
鳗鱼卡洛斯
我本来也还能得逞的
And I would have gotten away with it, too
都怪这全海底最烂的司机把我害惨了
if it wasn't for the worst driver in all the oceans
不知道他那是想说谁
I wonder who he meant by that
谢谢  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
继续吧
Do go on
然后  我跟加速下了山
Then, Acceleration and I went down the mountain
开过了浓雾
and we drove through the fog
撞上了坚冰
And we crashed on the ice
我好爱那故事  海绵宝宝
I love that story, SpongeBob
再讲一次吧
Tell it again